Guide to the Reference Center for Marxist Studies Pamphlet Collection PE.043
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Youth (33 pamphlets) (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Gus Hall Speaks on Youth Rights. Hall-Tyner Election Campaign Committee, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Hall, Gus. Which Way for Young Americans?. Challenge, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1950 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Job Problems of Youth. Youth Publications, Inc., New York, NY., undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Kay, Helen. We Demand: A Story of Any Boy and Any Girl. National Committee Unemployed Councils, New York, NY., undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Kropotkin, P. An Appeal to the Young. Charles H. Kerr and Company, Chicago, IL., undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Lenin Speaks to the Youth. International Publishers, New York, NY., 1937 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Michal, Wolf. Youth Marches Towards Socialism. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1936 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Our Generation Will Not Be Silent. Labor Youth League, New York, NY., 1953 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Richmond, Al. Campus Rebels. Pacific Publishing Foundation, San Francisco, CA., undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Starobin, Joseph. Its Up to You!. New Age Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Steele, Al. Lenin Liebknecht Luxemburg. Youth Publishers, New York, NY., 1934 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Steele, James. A Higher Ground for Struggle., undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Ward, Roosevelt. Toward Bright Tomorrows: World Youth Unites for Peace and Freedom. Challenge, New York, NY., 1950 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Weissman, Aaron. What's Behind "Juvenile Delinquency". New Century Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1955 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Wofsky, Leon. Youth Fights for Its Future. Labor Youth League, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1952 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Youth Faces the Elections. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1936 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Youth Seeks Peace Freedom and Progress. National Council American Youth Congress, New York, NY., undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Youth Unite for the Right to Earn, Learn, and Live!. Young Workers Liberation League, New York, NY., undated (Box 126, Folder 7)
- Youth: African Americans (contains an article and proceedings of the Negro Youth Conference (1938)) (Box 126, Folder 8)
  - Youth: African Americans (Box 126, Folder 8)
- Youth and Fascism (contains 2 pamphlets and a brochure) (Box 126, Folder 9)
  - Kuusinen, O. Youth and Fascism. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1935 (Box 126, Folder 9)
  - Schnapper, M. B. Youth Betrayed. International Relief Association, New York, NY., undated (Box 126, Folder 9)
- Youth and Jobs (9 pamphlets and 2 issues of American Child (1965)) (Box 126, Folder 10)
  - Davis, Kingsley. Youth in the Depression. University of Chicago Press, Chicago, IL., 1935 (Box 126, Folder 10)
  - Job Problems of Youth. Youth Publications, Inc., New York, NY. (3 copies), undated (Box 126, Folder 10)
  - Lewis, John L. Jobs Peace Unity. Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC. (3 copies), undated (Box 126, Folder 10)
  - No Slave Labor. New York Youth Congress, New York, NY., undated (Box 126, Folder 10)
  - The Young Worker Challenges the Union Establishment. United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (UE), New York, NY., undated (Box 126, Folder 10)
  - Youth Unemployment: Presenters to the United States Commission on Civil Rights., 1980 (Box 126, Folder 10)
- Youth and Peace (5 pamphlets) (Box 126, Folder 11)
  - Lerner, James. Youth Demands Peace. National Youth Committee American League Against War and Fascism, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1936 (Box 126, Folder 11)
  - Manning, Alfred. Youth Marches for Peace. American Youth Congress, Newark, NJ., undated (Box 126, Folder 11)
  - Weiss, Max. "In Flanders Field...". Youth Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1935 (Box 126, Folder 11)
- Youth: Students (1 pamphlet) (Box 126, Folder 12)
  - Leader, Lennie and Lennie Martin. Youth. Youth Commission Communist Party New York State., undated (Box 126, Folder 12)
- Youth Movements (6 pamphlets) (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - FSM. W.E.B. Dubois Clubs of America, San Francisco, CA., 1965 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Wofsky, Leon. Youth Fights for Its Future. Labor Youth League, New York, NY., 1952 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - The Fire This Time. W.E.B. Dubois Clubs of Los Angeles. (2 copies), 1965 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Building a Militant Student Movement: Program and Constitution of the National Student League., undated (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Is There an American Youth Movement. Agricultural Extension Service, College of Agriculture of the University of Wisconsin., undated (Box 127, Folder 1)
- Yugoslavia (12 pamphlets as well as a constitution and conference reports) (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Adamic, Louis. Struggle. Tomorrow Publishers, New York, NY., 1935 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Broz-Tito, Marshal Josip. Real Reasons Behind the Slanders Against Yugoslavia. Jugoslovenska Knjiga, Belgrade., 1949 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Edvard, Kardelj. Yugoslavia's Claim to Trieste. United Committee of South-Slavic Americans, New York, NY., undated (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Kurup, C. P. D. Yugoslavia at Crossroads: A Marxist Analysis of the Tito-Stalin Conflict. Published by the author, Bombay., undated (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Markovich, Mirko. The Yugoslavian Front Against Fascism. Slobodna Rech, Serbian Language Newspaper, Pittsburgh, PA. (2 copies), 1942 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Taylor, A. J. P. Trieste. United Committee of South-Slavic Americans, New York, NY., 1945 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - The Truth About Yugoslavia: A Documentary Record. Mirko Markovich, Pittsburgh, PA. (2 copies), undated (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Women and the Family in the New Yugoslavia. British-Yugoslav Association, London., 1947 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Youth Builds a Railway. British Yugoslav Association, London., 1947 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Yugoslavia: Progress of the 5-Year Plan. Embassy of the Federal Peoples Republic of Yugoslavia, Washington, DC., 1949 (Box 127, Folder 2)
- YWLL (8 pamphlets as well as statements and a constitution) (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Gus Hall Speaks on Youth Rights. Hall-Tyner Election Campaign Committee, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Hall, Gus. New Times Call for a New Communist Youth Organization. (2 copies), undated (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Steele, James. A Higher Ground for Struggle. (2 copies), undated (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - We Demand a Better Life for Our Generation. Young Workers Liberation League, New York, NY., 1977 (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Youth Unite for the Right to Earn, Learn, and Live!. Young Workers Liberation League, New York, NY., undated (Box 127, Folder 3)
- Zhivkov, Todor: Speeches (13 pamphlets) (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Zhivkov, Todor: Speeches (Box 127, Folder 4)
- Zionism I (12 pamphlets) (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Bakanov, B. Zionist Falsehoods. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1974 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - International Declarations: Zionism and Racism. Palestine Information Office, Washington, DC., 1981 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Jarblum, M. The Socialist International and Zionism. Poale Zion-Zeire Zion of America, New York, NY., 1933 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Lumer, Dr. Hyman and Meir Vilner. Zionism - Is It Racist? Two Statements on the UN Resolution. Committee for a Just Peace in the Middle East, New York, NY. (2 copies), undated (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Novick, Paul. Zionism Today. Jewish Buro of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of the U.S.A., New York. (4 copies), 1936 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Schappes, Morris U. The Strange World of Hannah Arendt. Jewish Currents, New York, NY., 1963 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Soviet Jews Reject Zionist "Protection". Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1971 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Zionism and the Arab Revolution: The Myth of Progressive Israel. Young Socialist Alliance, New York, NY., 1967 (Box 127, Folder 5)
- Zionism II (17 pamphlets) (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Communism: The Main Line of Zionism. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1972 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Zionist Committee of Soviet Public Opinion: Aims and Tasks. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1983 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Bolshakov, V. Anti-Sovietism - Profession of Zionists. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1971 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Borochov, Ber. Selected Essays in Socialist-Zionism. Rita Searl, London., 1948 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - British Labor and Zionism. The American Jewish Trade Union Committee for Palestine, New York, NY., undated (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Dadiani, Lionel. Zionism Through the Statements of Its Leaders. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow. (2 copies), 1986 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - David, Ben. Letter to a Zionist Friend. Jewish Pamphlet Library, New York., 1937 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Deceived by Zionism. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1971 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Dragunsky, David. What Letters Tell. Anti-Zionist Committee of Soviet Public Opinion, Moscow., 1984 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Goldstein, Dr. Israel. General Zionist Program. Zionist Organization of America, New York, NY., undated (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Novack, George. How Can the Jews Survive? A Socialist Answer to Zionism. Pathfinder Press, Inc., New York, NY., 1970 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Parties in Zionism: Their History and Programs. Zionist Organization of America, New York, NY., 1947 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Refaat, Kamal El-Din. The Zionist Strategy. International Confederation of Arab Trade Unions., undated (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Steinberg, Rabbi Milton. The Creed of an American Zionist. Committee on Unity for Palestine, New York, NY., undated (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Your Z.O.A. Its Place in the Zionist Movement. Zionist Organization of America, New York, NY., undated (Box 127, Folder 6)
- Spanish Language Pamphlets (258 pamphlets) (Box 129, Box 130)
  - 1930-1939 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - 1940-1949 I (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - 1940-1949 II (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - 1950-1959 (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - 1960-1969 I (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - 1960-1969 II (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - 1960-1969 III (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - 1960-1969 IV (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - 1960-1969 V (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - 1960-1969 VI (Box 129, Folder 10)
  - 1970-1979 I (Box 129, Folder 11)
  - 1970-1979 II (Box 129, Folder 12)
  - 1970-1979 III (Box 129, Folder 13)
  - 1970-1979 IV (Box 129, Folder 14)
  - 1970-1979 V (Box 129, Folder 15)
  - 1970-1979 VI (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - 1970-1979 VII (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - 1980-1989 I (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - 1980-1989 II (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - 1980-1989 III (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - 1980-1989 IV (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - 1980-1989 V (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - 1980-1989 VI (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - 1980-1989 VII (Box 130, Folder 9)
  - 1980-1989 VIII (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - 1990-1999 (Box 130, Folder 11)
  - undated I (Box 130, Folder 12)
  - undated II (Box 130, Folder 13)
  - undated III (Box 130, Folder 14)
  - undated IV (Box 130, Folder 15)
  - undated V (Box 130, Folder 16)